the feeling whenever I do something I
feel happy you see this is you try that
whatever you may have knowledge you have
sometimes bettering the economy you may
have better better baby sometime you can
have a kind words you can have so if we
use and make somebody's life happy that
you are giving and his or her life is a
happy that's a better best thing a human
being getting off that then you'll get a
card root conflict free world that's why
I used to say well there is
righteousness in the heart there's
beauty in the cat where there is beauty
in the character there is harmony in the
home harmony in the home where there is
harmony in the home there is order in
the nation when there is order in the
nation there's peace in the world this
is a starting point where there's a
righteousness the heart beauty in the
character harmony the hope and the order
in the nation peace in the world
all in one of the others coming so where
we start we start the righteous now
remember this incident 1979 1979 slv-3
satellite launch vehicle I were the
project director mission director my
mission is to put the satellite in the
orbit thousands of people work nearly
ten years I reach the I reach the Surrey
arakata condition the launch pad
countdown was going on
t-minus four minutes t-minus five
minutes t-minus two one one minute
t-minus 40 seconds computer put a hold
don't launch it computer say don't
launch it I am the mission director I
have to take decision everything is on
behind me there are six experts they saw
did a computer database coming in and
screen
they see the pictures the screen they
said there's a problem the problem is
there's a leakage in a system in the
control system but immediately
calculation no problem
we have got sufficient fuel and oxidiser
country control system is contorta
rocket to the record attitude and we can
go ahead now of course my experts view
but I took a division problems mine
right finally I took a division i bypass
the computer I launched the system okay
and August baseball event first state
you worked in a four stage rocket and
second stage got mad it went to spin
instead of putting the satellite in the
orbit it put in the Bay of Bengal
1979 it was a failure there's a failed
first time I experienced my failure
how'd he manage the failure success I
can manage so at that time we have great
man your great leader also sati stubborn
he comes to me I'm very tired working
nearly four months
it makes me up calm let her go for a
press conference
prosperous meeting there like this
number of people world press before all
this and that all the gadget they are
there I was really frightened I will be
the culprit because I'm the project
director Asian director what's at East
Awad said chairman Indian Space Coast
what the artist said dear friends we
have failed today he is the first time I
have to do all the success all the
failure is I want to support my
technologists and scientists and staff
so that next year they succeed so he
took the whole range missile and then
media asked you put way off then got so
many crows we are putting like that lot
of criticism he received a criticism he
assured them in a year will succeed with
our team is a very good team next year
here only interesting happened next year
July 18 1980 when he succeeded president
said you go and conduct the press
conference do you follow what it means
it means when the failure occurred the
leader took it up
when the success came he gives to his
team how did you become so great great
that's a question well which class you
are singing what's your dream in life
singen well you know give their related
terms so I personally believe you Basava
dream say you must I must have a dream
I must continuously acquire knowledge
continuously acquire knowledge hard work
hard work and perseverance one should
not be a not afraid of problems we
should know how to handle the not only
how to handle success how to handle the
failures particularly you are in the
management environment return it I want
the young people to understand how to
manage the failure because any tasks you
do you have to come across problem
problem should not become the captain of
the individual or a project chief and
the project chief should become the
captain of the problems and defeat the
problem at site and for a culture of
excellence the reaction is not by
accident it is a process where an
individual continuously strives to
better oneself the performance standards
are set by themselves they work on their
dreams with focus and are prepared to
take calculated risk and do not get
deterred by failures as they move
towards their dreams then this type of
their dreams as they tend to reach the
original targets there's tried to work
to their potential in the process they
increase their performance there by
multiplying further their potential
this is an onion being lifecycle
phenomena culture of excellence they are
not in competition with genuine arts but
themselves that is a culture of
excellence I'm sure each one of you will
aspire to become a unique with culture
of excellence she has written books
you've served as president your
aerospace engineer you've been a
professor but you say the title you like
best is the title of teacher why is that
you know I had I had a teacher
I never say young boy ten years boy what
am the second world was going on at that
time I used to see in my class fifth
class teacher in science teacher he say
mr. subrahmanya he entered to the
classroom and abused to see the
radiation of knowledge from radius of
knowledge from him when he enters the
classroom my teacher I see a radiation
of purity of life and he's the way he
thought I my dream has got shaped what
should be my way of life he's the person
the teacher gave me the vision of my
life when I was a young fellow now a
teacher has got a fantastic opportunity
to grow minds to enrich the minds and
you the dreams to the young people and
nurture the dreams with them and they
would become a great human being
sometime they would become better than
you but better than the teacher so that
happens you to have and also there's a
teacher like what I am doing I am a
professor I can also do the research
young researchers will be work with me
that's a great pressure when they get
the PhD history has proven history has
proven that those who dare to imagine
the impossible are the ones who break
all the human limitations in every field
of human endeavor whether science
medicine sports are the technology the
names of the people just know I listed
some of the names the names of the
people who imagine the impossible are
engraved in our history by breaking the
limits of the imagination by breaking
their limits of their magnet the change
they change the world
you take CV Raman you take Newton you
take angsting you take Chandra Shekar
thereby breaking the limits of their
imaging imagination they change the
world but carefully hear me what M say I
learned what did I learn from the youth
of 11 million people I learnt the over
youth wants to be unique paper youth
watch three unique that is you the over
you taught to be unique that is you but
the world around around you is doing it
best they might to make you just be
everybody else now whether you want to
be you re variants you you want to be
you not everybody else now if the coach
be like everybody else is convenient at
the first class but not satisfying in
the long vision the challenge there for
my young friends is that you have to
find hardest battle to fight the hardest
battle which any human being can never
imagine to fight and never stop fighting
until you
arrive at your destination dat is the
unique view to get to get the unique
view it's a big battle the battlements
you don't even take a garden the battle
means you have to have four unique
things for you know she must have that
battle one is your to set the goal the
second one is acquired the knowledge
continuously and third one it's a hard
work with the devotion and fourties
perseverance these are the tools you
have to either before the battle the
video TV if you want with discoverers if
you want to be innovators I am going to
give you what type of what type of
characteristic you must have the
invention and discoveries have Y
emanated from creativeminds that have
been constantly working and amazing the
outcome the telephone he was amazing the
outcome you making the outcome in the
mind with the imaging and constantly
effort all the forces of the universe
worked for that inspired mind thereby
leading to invention discoveries see I
have the feeling whenever I do something
I feel happy you see this is you trying
and that whatever you may have knowledge
you hope sometimes better the economy
may have better better maybe sometimes
you have a kind words you can have so if
we use and make somebody's life happy
that you are giving and his or her life
is a happy that's a better bet the best
idea
because they that then you get a car to
conflict-free world that is leader
should work with integrity and succeed
with a better leader work with integrity
and succeed in London and I believe
president since you asked the question
has to be continuously in touch with the
people rush to the woman bare eyes I was
there became a people spell and so
crossed over the women it becomes
people's power and also I travel into
the whole state cutting across Hill
deserts and see I was in touch with
millions and millions of